computernetworkingnotes.com 2019-06-21

# Privacy Policy

ComputerNetworkingNotes recognizes that your privacy is very important and we take it seriously. This privacy policy describes what information we collect from you or what information you share with us when you visit our website.

### Personal Information

Personal Information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including but not limited to a first and last name, company name, e-mail address, telephone number, physical address, billing information, etc.

We do not collect any personal information from our users. Users are free to navigate through our website without registration and providing any personally identifiable information.

### Aggregate or Non-Personal Information

Aggregate or non-personal information is the information which does not include any personal identifiable information. As users navigate through our website certain aggregate or non-personal information are collected anonymously using various technologies such as web server logs, beacons and cookies as described below.

### Web server logs

When you visit our website, we may track information related to website usage to administer the website. Examples of information we may collect includes your internet protocol address, what type of browser or computer you use, the number of links you click within the website, the state or country from which you accessed the website, the date and time of your visit, the name of your internet services provider, the last page you viewed before visiting our website, and the pages you viewed on the website.

### Beacons

A web beacon is a small and unnoticeable image served by the third party advertiser in order to collect information from your browser to compile aggregated statistics regarding our website. We use Google AdSense and several other third party advertisers to serve ads in our website. They may include a web beacon to confirm that their ads are being served correctly.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of text that allows a website to recognize your device and maintain a consistent, cohesive experience throughout multiple sessions. We use cookies to customize the content of our services to your preferences and optimize the services.

In particular, cookies enable to identify your device and display the service in the correct manner, e.g. its website, customized to your individual needs; create statistics that help us understand how you use the website, so that we can improve its structure and content; and offer personalized marketing communications once you have provided us with the relevant legal basis. Storage of cookies does not change configuration of your device or software installed on it.

#### THE TYPES OF COOKIES WE USE

The following types of cookies may be used when you visit our site:

##### Advertising Cookies

Advertising cookies are placed on your computer by advertisers and ad servers in order to display advertisements that are most likely to be of interest to you. These cookies allow advertisers and ad servers to gather information about your visits to our website and other websites, alternate the ads sent to a specific computer, and track how often an ad has been viewed and by whom. These cookies are linked to a computer and do not gather any personal information about you.

##### Analytics Cookies

Analytics cookies monitor how users reached to our website, and how they interact with and move around once arrived on our website. These cookies let us know what features on website are working the best and what features should be improved.

##### First-Party Cookies

First-party cookies are used by a website for its internal purpose. Certain feature and function of a website depend on first party cookies. Although you can, still you should not disable or block first party cookies. These are necessary cookies. Our website will not work without these cookies.

##### Personalization Cookies

Personalization cookies are used to recognize the repeat visitors We use these cookies to record your browsing history, the pages you have visited, and your settings and preferences each time you visit our website.

##### Security Cookies

Security cookies help identify and prevent security risks. We use these cookies to authenticate users and protect user data from unauthorized parties.

##### Third-Party Cookies

Third-party cookies may be placed on your computer when you visit our website by companies that run certain services we offer. These cookies allow the third parties to gather and track certain anonymous information about our users.

 **We use cookies to:**

  * Improve the speed of the site
  * Continuously improve our website for you
  * Allow you to share pages with social networks like Facebook, Twitter, etc.
  * Offer you free services/content (by advertising)
  * Make our marketing more efficient (helping us keep the site free to use)

 **We do not use cookies to:**

  * Collect any personally identifiable information (without your express permission)
  * Collect any sensitive information (without your express permission)
  * Pay sales commissions

#### Granting us permission to use cookies

If your browser is adjusted to accept cookies we take this, and your continued use of our website, to mean that you are fine with this. Should you wish to deactivate cookies, you can learn how to do it in your choices section, however doing so will likely mean that your browser will not work as you would expect on most web pages.

### Advertisement

To help us maintain the resources needed to create the quality content you deserve, we show adverts as you browse our site. These adverts are usually managed by a partner specializing in providing adverts for multiple sites. Invariably these partners place advertising cookies to collect anonymous data about the websites you visits so they can personalize the adverts to you, ensure that you don't see the same adverts too frequently and ultimately report to advertisers on which adverts are working.

### Google AdSense

We use Google AdSense to serve ads in our website. Google AdSense uses one or more advertising cookies to serve ads based on your visit to our website or other websites on the Internet. To learn more about how Google AdSense sets and uses advertising cookies, you can check this web page.

<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to compile visitor statistics such as how many people have visited our website, what type of technology they are using (e.g. Mac or Windows which helps to identify when our site isn't working as it should for particular technologies), how long they spend on the site, what page they look at etc. Google analytics uses analytic cookies.

How we use the non-personal information collected by us

We may use aggregate or non-personal information to administer, maintain and improve our website. This information can be used for internal/external marketing purposes to analyze trends and summarize statistics. It can also provide information about interests and preferences of our users which enables us to target the section or category that users may find helpful and informative.

We may disclose aggregate information and other non-personally identifiable information for various purposes at our sole discretion in an effort to customize or enhance the content and advertising of our website.

## Your choices

Although we make every effort to collect as little information as necessary to ensure our site and services run smoothly, still you may opt out from providing this information by following methods.

### Deleting and blocking beacons

To block beacons from our site or from any other site, you can install and use any standard ad-blocker plugin or simply can disable JavaScript in your browser. To delete already severed beacons, you can clear your browser or device history.

### Deleting and blocking cookies

All most all modern web browsers have options to control the cookies. These options are usually found in the 'options' or 'preferences' menu of your browser. These options allow you to delete or block cookies from individual website or from all websites.

If cookies settings options are not available at this location, you can check help section of that particular browser or device, or can visit the one of the following links that corresponds to your device and browser:

If your device or browser is not listed in above list or you want to learn what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, you can visit www.allaboutcookies.org

### Opting out from Google Analytics

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. This add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity. You can download this add-on from here

<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

To learn how Google Analytics uses cookies, collects and uses user data and how can you decline Google Analytics from setting cookies and collecting data from your browser or device, see following web pages.

<https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

<https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>

### Opting out from Google AdSense interest-based advertising

If you are not interested in personalized ads from Google AdSense, login in your Google account and opt out from personalized advertising by visiting following web page.

<https://www.google.com/settings/ads>

To learn more about how Google AdSense sets and uses advertising cookies, you can check this web page.

<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

### Opting out from third party interest-based advertising

To opt out from third party interest-based advertising, visit corresponding organization

USA: - <http://aboutads.info/choices>

Others: - <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices.>

Europe: - <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>

Canada: - [http://www.youradchoices.ca](http://www.youradchoices.ca/)

### Children's privacy

We are committed to protecting children's privacy online. This website is intended for users above the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect information from children. Children under 13 should ask a parent, guardian or teacher for permission before sending us any information online.

### Linking to other websites

Our website may contain links to other third party sites and social sharing sites such Facebook, twitter, LinkedIn, etc. These sites are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. Once you have left our website you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party website to determine how they will handle any information they collect from you.

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

##### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by using the email ComputerNetworkingNotes@gmail.com
